That all the information related to vehicle insurance is available from the
insurance company or the
brokerage side of the insurance company
like policybazaar.com or Coverfox which is
also a new company which keeps telling you all day long through TV, internet and
social media whether the
Equal C policy is good or
how to choose a better company, what things should you keep in mind while taking a policy, whether
online is good or
offline is good, all this information is
available to you all day long but these people never
tell you how to take a claim, the
purpose of your taking the policy, this information about it, if there is an accident to
my vehicle, then
according to the insurance policy, the
insurance companies will repair my vehicle and compensate for the loss,
but you do not know the process, so let us
know that
after taking an insurance policy, if there is
any damage to your vehicle, any damage occurs, an
accident happens, then there is a
process to get the liability of its repair compensated from the insurance companies, do it, do it, in case of
any damage accident to your vehicle, first of all it is
very important for you to do two things, first of all you should
inform the insurance company about it on time,
by the way insurance companies say that two
working  Day means hundred and you
inform me within this and maximum it can be one week,
so you should keep this thing in mind that
whenever there is any damage accident in your car,
secondly if the damage
is big or it has happened between two people in
which there can be any big liability, then
keep a video or a photo of that damage and also
keep it in the police complaint, the insurance
can ask for it from you while processing the claim,
after that your formal claim
process starts, for this you
can mention the number in your policy or google it,
according to your company and brokerage side a
toll free number is mentioned in the policy,
you complain on that toll free number,
after making the complaint the
people sitting in customer care there give you a reference number, this is called
question number, they generate it and for
further process they
tell you where you have to take your car,
if your car
is not in the damaged condition, that means it is damaged in such a way that
your car cannot go from there, then the
address of insurance like cement,
they come to the spot and take the car  They
assess the insurance cover, otherwise you take your car
to the designated place mentioned by them,
it is a garage, after going there
you have to complete the insurance process,
in a copy you have to fill up the form that
how many insurance companies you have to
subscribe to and
submit an application to the
insurance company, in which the necessary things are to be mentioned,
secondly and thirdly driving license and
fourthly your claim form, after submitting this
you get your car repaired
anywhere as per that calculation,
after your car is repaired you
take a bill of it and the insurance company also
submits the bill to that company, if the garage is of cashless
type, that is it was
some type of garage of the insurance company itself which is
called cashless balance, if the repair was done in that garage
then you do not need to do anything,
after repairing the car you submit it to you
and your claim process gets
over, but if your car was
repaired in a private garage
which was not with the term insurance company, then
you take a bill of whatever repair was done
in your car from there and
you also submit this to the insurance companies  You do this
because
you have to make the payment to that private garage first
and then you submit the money for reimbursement to the insurance company to
get the money that you had given for your duty. The
insurance company pays your bill as per the
calculation done by you
and you get your money reimbursed
and your car gets repaired.
So this entire process
from depositing it in your car to getting it repaired by the insurance company on that day is
not a very difficult process. Now it has become very
easy. Every company has to
come under a condition. They feel that the sooner the
claim settlement happens, the
better the public perception will be, the
better it will be for my company. So it is very tasty
nowadays insurance companies start their process as soon as you
give a call that my car has suffered some
damage. They
take their own initiative and contact you and
repair your car by helping you. So
friends, till this point, the entire process of getting your
car repaired by the insurance company is shown.
If you like this video then  Please give a like
and don't forget to subscribe to the channel.
This is butter paper.